# **Kensuke Morris**

# **Data Analyst**

### **Contact**

### **Objective**

Kyoto City, Japan kensuke.morris@gmail.com LinkedIn Data analyst skilled in data exploration and communicating data insights from multiple standpoints to solve business and research problems, especially for culture-specific projects. Previously utilized combined quantitative and qualitative methods to develop a patient-centered proposal for patient data sharing on a nationwide level.

### **Education**

### **Projects**

Certificate in Data Analytics | 2/2021 – 9/2021

CareerFoundry (Online)
Intense, project-based courses

Ph.D. in Informatics | 2020 Minor in Design Kyoto University

MS in Informatics | 2017 *Kyoto University* 

B.Sc. Info. Technology | 2014 St. George's University

## **Key Skills**

Data-driven Inquiry
Data Cleaning
Data Exploration
Database Querying
Statistical Analysis
Regression Analysis
Machine Learning
Storytelling
Team Coordination

### Languages

Software: Python | R PostgreSQL | HTML

#### Spoken:

English (Native)
Japanese (Conversation)
Spanish (Elementary)

#### **Emergency Department Discharge Encounters**

View

Conducted a preliminary investigation of patient encounters related to patient race groups and ED discharge types in California using Python and Tableau.

#### **Instacart Customer Behaviour**

View

Performed exploratory analysis of customer data to derive insights and suggested strategies for better customer segmentation using Python and Tableau.

### **Experience**

#### Research Fellow • 4/2021 - current

National Cerebral and Cardiovascular Center • Japan

- Obtained valuable insights for a healthcare device company using health related data. Utilized survival and regression analysis techniques.
- Selected predictive features of patients with a cardiovascular-related disease using the boruta technique, random forest, and lasso/ridge regression.

#### Researcher • 10/2020 - 3/2021

Kyoto University Hospital • Japan

- Developed the first draft API documentation based on my Ph.D. research related to patient data sharing to assist a health records vendor in developing tools to future system integration.
- Supported students in developing their research techniques related to user research, especially quantitative survey design and interview techniques.

#### **Assistant Director** • 8/2014 – 2/2015

Centre for Academic Excellence, St. George's University • Grenada

• Monitored student performance reports (incl. GPAs) based on ethical guidelines to identify students at risk of expulsion and notified their student advisors with an intervention plan.

#### Sales Agent • 7/2012 - 7/2014

Digicel • Grenada

• Appointed team leader on three consecutive occasions to lead our sales team to surpass sales targets for data plan activations for a biannual event.